Agustí Bau Pericón

■agustibau@gmail.com □+34699540050 ■ in/agustibau • www.agustibau.com

Hey! I'm Agustí a software engineer with about 7 years of experience. I enjoy work when I build products that are useful to people. I like being surrounded by bright people, I like coding in vim, building scripts and all that madness.

Here follows a one page summary of my professional career:

WHEN WORKING Focus on business value Finishing work is easier said than done Two or three minds think better than one Find problems, build solutions Professional but fun Each line, function, module should do one thing Everything should have some test Mindful about complexity Any rule above can be broken, with a good enough reason

EXPERIENCE

Senior software Engineer - Clovr-labs

Jan 2022 - present, Barcelona

I'm part of the chain* team, where we build a highly scalable blockchain analytics system, mainly using python, spark, and redis on kubernetes. Alongside the team, we design, architect and develop the whole solution. Taking into consideration: performance, developer experience and scalability. The main problems we are usually dealing with:

- Due to sparseness of graph data, providing fast access to random parts of the graph is complicated
- Because big data tools are used. Problems like number of connections from/to machines, resource usage, parallelization of processes occur.

Senior software Engineer - Kasaz

Jul 2020 - Jan 2022, Barcelona

We operated fully remote. I did everything required to keep the platform rolling, backend (ruby on rails), frontend (react, react native and graphql) and devops (AWS). I did also onboard and somewhat manage the newcomers that joined the company

Some of the features that we built:

- Search listings by drawing a hand-drawn area or panning the map automatically
- Feed generation to be ingested by traffic providers, involving complex queries that have to run for any amount of listings.
- Alert system to keep users up to date with new listings according to saved searches

Startup incubator - Zinc.vc

Sept 2019 - Feb 2020, London

I was part of "mission 3" where we looked for startup possiblities "for the older population".

Software engineer - Datatiger

Oct 2017 - Nov 2018, London

At Datatiger we built a marketing tool, horizontally scalable following a microservices architecture using mainly Java and Python on Docker and AWS.

- I was the 8th hire, we developed, designed, and architected key main features of the platform.
- I was responsible of integrating our platform with different systems (email providers, other event providers, ad networks, among others).
- I developed the first parts of the analytics system based on a data lake architecture.

Junior software engineer - King

Jun 2016 - Sep 2017, Barcelona

We developed a marketing internal system built on Jboss, AWS Redshift and Kafka, using Agile methodologies.

- I implemented end to end image notifications across all King games.
- I developed multiple backend features that incorporated into an ETL process.

Remote For Mac - Self-employed

2013 - 2016~

While in university I developed an Android app, a remote control for Mac devices, for Android. Over time it got downloaded over 200k times, and netted some student money. Better competitors appeared and I lost interest.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's degree in computer science

Barcelona School of Informatics • Barcelona • 2018 • 7.3 (out of 10)